José Miguel Quesada Campos Frontend Developer

Caracas, Venezuela josesk8mqc@gmail.com (+58) 4122120037

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-quesada-ecodeveloper/ https://ecodeveloper.me/

Frontend developer with 2 years of experience, working on projects that will be used for people all around the country, using technologies such as JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, and Ionic. I excel at problem-solving and adding value to the companies I work for.

Experience

Prolesys Consultores C.A.

July, 2022 – August, 2023

Frontend Developer

- Contributed to the development of four currently operational applications that are being utilized by millions of users across the country.
- Created a cross-platform application for both web and mobile devices using Ionic, React and TypeScript.
- Led the successful development of two frontend projects with React, overseeing the entire process from design to deployment.
- Participated in the strategic planning and organization of the projects I was involved in, intending to develop robust and scalable applications.
- Created code that is both reusable and scalable, resulting in a reduction of overall code volume and improved app performance.

Fibex Telecom

September, 2021 - July, 2022

Fullstack Developer

- Contributed to the development of five applications currently in production, catering to a nationwide user base, compatible with web, tablet, mobile, and TV devices.
- Led the development of one fullstack geolocation application, developing the frontend React, the backend with Node.js and TypeScript, overseeing the entire process from design to deployment.
- Developed a mobile and television cross-platform OTT application with Ionic. Angular and TypeScript.
- Designed and implemented scalable microservices architecture using Node.js and PHP, seamlessly integrating them into multiple applications.

Technologies

JavaScript

TypeScript

Ionic

• Frameworks CSS

React

• Redux

Nextis

Gatsby

Nodeis

• Express

• SQL

Git

Languages

Spanish: Native Ingles: C2

Education

Universidad Central de Venezuela

2017 - Present

Economy